Welcome back everyone. So now you are going to
欢迎回来 现在你要开始
actually start changing the data into batches.
将数据生成批次了
You are going to be creating batches for this to pass into the network.
你将生成若干批次并将其传递给网络
So remember, with skip-gram architecture,
记住 用 skip-gram 结构的时候
we're going to take one word and then we're going to use the words
我们要取一个单词
that are around that word in the text as targets right,
并以该词所处文本周围的单词作为目标
so to use as the context around whatever input word we have.
也就是说无论输入单词是什么 我们都会以获取该词的上下文作为目标
So basically for every word,
所以在处理各单词时
we're going to grab a window of words around it and that
我们要抓取一个由输入词周围单词组成的窗口
window's going to have some size C. So then what
这个窗口的大小为 C
Mikalov did is they actually chose like some random range within this window.
Mikalov 做的其实就是在窗口里随机选择一个范围
So the reason they did this is because distant words
这么做是因为远些的单词
are usually less related to whatever input word you have,
往往与输入单词关系较浅
than the ones that are close to it.
而近些的单词则较深
So basically you just want to kind of de-emphasize words that
所以你要弱化相对较远的单词
are further away as compared to words that are closer.
这个远是相对于那些离输入单词较近的词来说的
So then if you have some windows C say it's like five,
假设你的窗口大小为 C 假设 C 等于 5
then what you're going to do is select
你得在
some random number R that's in a range of like one to C. So
1 到 C 之间选一个随机数 R
basically you're just choosing like randomly a smaller window from
这么做相当于你随机在大窗口里
your large window and then we are- smaller window which is defined by R,
选了一个由 R 定义的小窗口
you just grab the words from the past and R words from the future.
在小窗口里 你要以在输入单词前和后的 R 个单词
And then you're going to use these as correct labels.
作为正确的标签
So what this does is you're basically always likely
这样一来
to get words that are right next to your current word,
你就总能得到现有单词旁边的单词
but you're less likely to get words that are further away from your current word.
至于那些离现有单词较远的词 则获取的概率会比较小
And so what you're really doing is going to be training on
所以你会更频繁地训练
words that are closer to your current word, more often.
那些离现有单词较近的词
So what you'll be doing here is actually implementing this.
你要在这里实现这些操作
Like, so, you're going to get the target words.
也即获取目标单词
So you get a pass in a string of words and then an
所以你要输入一串单词
index which is your current word and then you're going to grab
和一个索引 也就是现有单词 然后在索引周围抓取一个窗口
a window from around the index and basically return all the target words in that window.
并返回窗口里的所有目标单词
But you're also going to be using- like
但你还要用
you're going to find like some this random range R and then only
你还要找出这个随机范围 R
return words that are in that smaller window R. And then once you have that written,
然后只返回出小窗口 R 里的单词 等你写好了实现代码
this is a function that's going to return
这就是你要用的批次返回函数了
our batches so the data that we're going to pass into the network.
也就是我们要传递给网络的数据
So what this is going to do is going to grab some words from our, you know,
这个函数会从长长的文本列表 也就是整数列表里
big text list or list of integers
抓取一些单词
and for each of those words it's going to get the targets.
然后获取每个单词的目标 也就是应用函数 get_targets
So like the target words that show up in the window which you implement here.
换句话说 用你在这上面实现的函数来获取出现在窗口里的目标单词
So I haven't found a good way to like make
我还没找到什么好办法
this random number of target words actually work with the TensorFlow graph.
把目标单词的这个随机获取范围和 TensorFlow 图结合起来
So basically what I did here is just make
所以这里我就只是
each of those like input target pairs one row in the batch.
在批次里设置一行一个输入目标对
So then if you have some current word and then there's
比如说 一个现有单词
four target words then I'm going to make those into four different rows in the batch.
对应四个目标单词 那我就在批次里将其做成四行
So four input target pairs.
因为有四个输入目标对
Okay, so here just go ahead and try to implement this get_target function.
好了 动手吧 试着实现这个函数 get_target
And as always you can check out my solution in the notebook or my video. Cheers.
和之前一样 你可以到 notebook 或视频里查看我的解决方案 加油